# Sarker Jawad Islam

Birmingham, UK • +44 7535 982265 • saadislam443@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Willing to Relocate

# **GRADUATE/JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Highly Qualified Junior Software Developer with extensive knowledge and skills in android and web application development. Experienced in utilising different methodologies, such as Waterfall and Agile, GitHub, Android Studio, Visual Basic Studio, Unity for software development. Proven expertise in implementing SCRUM in final year project for development due to incremental development.

- <u>Final Year Project /Waiting Time App</u>: Developed an app for A&E simulation scenario using Java, PHP, and XML with Android Studio. The final product aims to improve the communication flow between staff/patients during long wait.
- <u>Game development (Three level platformer game</u>: Developed three-level game using C#, Unity and Visual Basic Studio. Game contained diverse range of gameplay and appropriate level challenge.
- App Development (Medication App (Health Aid): Group project of five members to create application using Agile methodology and Android Studio. Created medication screen whilst focusing on back end and link database to overall application. Implemented methods to display data in Medication screen. Linked all major screens of app by creating Navigation screen. Coordinated work between team members to improve performance and debug all screens.
- <u>Software Development- Finch Robot</u>: Team leader in group project to recreate Simon game using robot "Finch" to input/output certain colours. Programmed robot to complete set of activities such as draw a pattern. Conducted research to solve problems with program to raise quality of code. Implemented on/Off switch to improve game usability.
- Researching world languages and their relationship: Facilitated in collecting research for personal tutors' project which explored relationship between world languages and produced language tree.
- <u>Web Development</u>: Created improved version of my school' website to enhance learning about HTML and JavaScript programming and web development. Focused on programming main codes from scratch in Dreamweaver instead of using icons which automatically generate code.

#### Core Technologies:

Environments: Android Studio, Unity, GitHub, Microsoft office, Notepad++, Linux, SPSS,

Methodology Waterfall and Agile/Scrum

Applications: Visual Studio, Dreamweaver, Eclipse.

Tools: Java, XML, C#, MySQL, HTML, PHP, XML, R, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, JS/Node, Python.

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – 2017 - 2020

Brunel University - London, UK • First Class Honours Graduate

#### **EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

# **Bright Network Virtual Technology Internship**

Intern, 2020 - 2020

Carried out in depth research about facial verification in apps before designing a detailed project plan and sprint stages on how to implement it in a banking app. Used user stories to highlight key risks and identify important features required for the software. Presented a detailed report stating the project management, communication and release plan that had to be followed to ensure a successful project.

# Primark

#### Customer Assistant, 2017 – 2018

Provided excellent customer support ensuring to resolve issues related products in calm and efficient manner. Collaborated with team to restock products and organised items in proper order and place. developed negotiation skills while supporting customers pick products focusing product suits customer' need and budget. Delivered customer services to increase customer' positive shopping experience.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

E-Certificate from Bright Network Technology Internship | Received an E-certificate in SoloLearn for a Java Tutorial Course & HTML Fundamentals Course | Nominated to showcase final year project at **Made in Brunel 2020** to industry professionals | Achieved a Jack Petchey Achievement Award for being an outstanding achiever.